welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive
克登利夫
in this video we're going to be adding
在这段视频中 我们将添加
video and audio effects so we're just
视频和音频效果 所以我们只是
going to go through some of the
我将经历一些
different effects that kdenlive has to
Kdenlive必须产生不同的影响
offer there's a lot of them solicits
提议他们中有很多人在拉客
gonna be a brief introduction of how to
我将简要介绍如何
apply the effects and some of the
应用效果和一些
different ways to use them
使用它们的不同方式
if you're curious of how we got to this
如果你好奇我们是怎么做到这一点的
point watch the last tutorial we
重点观看我们的最后一个教程
downloaded some footage and we just were
下载了一些素材 我们只是
just using this audio and video and we
只用这段音频和视频 我们
kind of created some different spaces
创造了一些不同的空间
I'll show you what this video looks like
我会让你看看这个视频是什么样子的
so we kind of we set up we split our
所以我们设立了我们把我们的
audio files so we have two different
音频文件 所以我们有两个不同的
audio clips and then we just kind of
音频片段 然后我们就像是
broke up these and we could have put
把这些打碎 我们就可以把
these all down on the same video track
所有这些都记录在同一个视频轨道上
but we have them on three separate
但我们有三个不同的版本
tracks just because we can and for fun
跟踪只是因为我们可以 为了好玩
I'm gonna to get started though I'm
我要开始了 虽然我是
gonna left click on this bottom most
我要左键点击最下面的
audio track I'm hit the Delete key and
音轨我按下了Delete键
we'll just delete that audio portion out
我们只需删除该音频部分
of there and yeah so we'll just we'll
在那里 是的 所以我们只是 我们将
leave the at the track we could delete
把它留在我们可以删除的曲目上
the track all together too by going to
所有的赛道也在一起 通过去
delete track but I'll just keep it in
删除曲目 但我只会保留它
there for now and again if you ever want
如果你想的话 现在就在那里
to add a track you can right click and
要添加曲目 您可以右键单击并
just insert you can add an audio track
只需插入即可添加音轨
or a video track in there as well so to
或者里面还有一首录像带 所以
apply effects let's say we want to have
应用效果比方说我们想要
each one of these different so every
每一个都不同 所以每一个
time it changes to its recent kind of
时间改变为它最近的一种
goes black then it resets and shows a
变黑 然后重置并显示
different portion let's let's change on
我们换一份吧 换一份
just on the video let's see if we can
就在视频里 让我们看看我们能不能
grab a nice video effect to change the
抓取一个不错的视频效果来改变
look of the video every time it goes to
每次去看视频的时候
a different clip so we'll start with
一个不同的片段 所以我们将从
this one here and these are the
这张是这里的 这些是
different effects we have to play with
我们必须处理不同的效果
so we can click this little triangle and
所以我们可以点击这个小三角形
it brings up different effects and if
它带来了不同的效果 如果
you have an effect in mind you can also
你心里有一个效果 你也可以
just type it in like mute for audio we
只需像静音一样输入音频即可
can mute the audio or we can do like a
可以将音频静音 或者我们可以像
zoom and so like position and zoom I'm
变焦 就像位置和变焦 我是
not sure what we have as far as eye
我不确定我们目前有什么
color goes so I'll type in color so we
颜色会消失 所以我会输入颜色 这样我们
have all these different things under
把所有这些不同的东西都放在下面
miscellaneous under color let's try like
五花八门的颜色让我们试一试
this Technicolor I actually don't know
这是彩色的 我其实不知道
what it does if we hover over it it
如果我们将鼠标悬停在上面 它会做什么
tells us over saturate the colors in a
告诉我们将颜色过度饱和
video like
视频点赞
old Technicolor movies okay cool so if
旧的彩色电影好的 很酷 所以如果
we want to use this one I'm gonna left
我们想用这个 我要走了
click and just drag it over top of
单击并只需将其拖动到
whatever clip we want it to go in let's
不管我们想把它放进什么剪辑里 让我们
put it in this first one and then it
先把它放进这个 然后放进去
brings up these properties over here and
把这些房产带到这里来
again if depending on your layout and
同样 根据您的布局和
the everythings are always changing from
每件事都在不断变化
different releases that it may be
它可能是不同的版本
different but we can move this so for
不同 但我们可以把这个移到
example we could put it in here and then
例如 我们可以把它放在这里 然后
it appears as a tab below so see now we
它出现在下面的选项卡中 现在请看我们
have all of our effects like we had
让我们所有的效果都像以前一样
before but then if we want to see the
在此之前 但如果我们想看到
properties of that effect we click on
我们点击该效果的属性
properties or I can left-click and drag
属性或我可以左键单击并拖动
and put it in its own window here which
把它放在它自己的窗户里
is what I've done okay so the properties
就是我所做的一切 所以这些物业
for get to wherever the properties for
要到达任何位置 请访问
that those this effects is properties
这些影响就是属性
are and then we can look at some
然后我们可以看看一些
different ways we can change them so by
我们可以通过不同的方式来改变它们
default we see if we go to the clip
默认情况下 如果我们转到剪辑 我们会看到
ahead we see this one looks normal
前面我们看到这个看起来很正常
ish and this one's kind of more the
ISH 而这一次更像是
colors are a lot more dramatic we can
我们可以用更具戏剧性的颜色
make them even more if we want to get
如果我们想要得到更多
completely like really dramatic effect
完全喜欢非常戏剧化的效果
yeah this is a pretty good Technicolor
是的 这是一种很好的彩色照片
filter that's cool so this is the
过滤器很酷 所以这是
original and then this is the improved
原来的 然后这是改进的
one we'll just leave this exactly how it
一 我们只会让它保持原样
is now let's move on to our next clip
现在让我们继续我们的下一个片段
and let's find a different kind of for
让我们找到一种不同类型的
this one let's do a cover rise to so
这一张 让我们做一个封面 上升到
under cover eyes we can hover over and
在遮盖的眼睛下 我们可以在上面盘旋
see colorize images to select hue
请参阅为图像上色以选择色调
saturation lightness so that's good I'm
饱和度 亮度 所以这很好 我
the left click and drag this one in and
左键单击并将此按钮拖入并
this one will just leave well will couch
这一张就会离开Well Will沙发
we can change the saturation of this
我们可以改变这个的饱和度
color the lightness and darkness let's
把光明和黑暗涂上颜色 让我们
make let's make it a little bit more
让我们做得更多一点
dark maybe and then the hue is gonna be
也许是黑暗 然后色调就会变得
that the color that we have it be so you
我们拥有的颜色就是你
know one cool effect might be to just
我知道一个很酷的效果可能就是
colorize each one of these a different
将这些颜色设置为不同的颜色
color but let's let's make this one what
颜色 但让我们把这个做成什么？
we're going to do red let's make it
我们要跳红色的 让我们成功吧
doesn't really matter yeah sure we'll
真的不重要是的我们肯定会的
make it red alright cool so now we have
让它变红吧 好吧 酷 所以现在我们有了
this one which is like full bright color
这一件颜色很鲜艳
this is the original kind of what's
这是原创的那种
going to then it's gonna get intense
然后就会变得激烈起来
saturation then it's gonna go to like
饱和 然后它会变得像
this red a little bit darker alright
这个红色稍微暗一点 好吗？
what should we do for this third clip
我们应该为这第三个片段做些什么
let's watch and see what we have so far
让我们来看看我们到目前为止都有什么
just so you know what's going on
只是想让你知道发生了什么事
[Music]
[音乐]
yeah it kind of went a little bit fast
是啊 进展得有点快
but that's okay so let's go here to this
但这没关系 让我们来看看这个
third clip and let's see what we have if
第三个片段 让我们看看我们有什么
I delete everything here let's try maybe
我把这里的所有东西都删除了 让我们试一试
this blur let's make one like really
这个模糊 让我们来做一个真的
blurry so let's go to this blur we hover
模糊 所以让我们去我们盘旋的模糊
over blur using 2d iir filters okay
可以使用2D IIR滤镜进行模糊处理
let's try that
让我们试一试
so we'll hover we'll drag this blur and
所以我们会盘旋 我们会拖着这个模糊
to this third one and then we see the
到这第三个 然后我们看到
the type of blur we want to do so this
我们要执行此操作的模糊类型
is low-pass what we have now and then
是我们时不时拥有的低传球
the amount we don't want to get too
我们不想得到的金额太多
crazy sometimes with these if with the
有时会疯狂地使用这些IF和
effects it's not as refined as some
效果不像有些人那么精致
software so if you try to mix effects
软件 所以如果你试图混合效果
and your you specify like if we type in
你指定如果我们输入的话
a million here it might actually crash
在这里一百万 它可能真的会坠毁
kdenlive especially on windows maybe not
Kdenlive 尤其是在Windows上 也许不是
so much on linux but so just be careful
关于Linux的内容太多了 所以要小心
to not ever get too crazy with some of
永远不会对一些人太疯狂
these but here we have a nice blur so
这些 但在这里我们有一个很好的模糊
we'll get a look at pretty extreme blur
我们将会看到相当极端的模糊
there we go so now we'll have our kind
我们走了 所以现在我们会有我们的同类
of saturated look Technicolor we have
我们有一种饱和的彩色图案
our red color this one just gonna be
我们的红色这一件将会是
blur and then this one is gonna be
模糊 然后这一个将会是
irregular again until till we change it
再次不规律 直到我们改变它
and so again it applies it to this whole
所以它再一次将它应用于整个
clip and the reason it's doing these
剪辑及其执行这些操作的原因
clips we put this black space in between
剪辑我们把这个黑色的空间放在中间
we didn't have to do that but anything
我们没必要这么做 但什么都可以
the whole duration of the clip if we
剪辑的整个持续时间如果我们
were to apply it a fill and effect to
将其应用于填充和效果
this the whole extents of this red
这就是这红色的全部范围
selection box is what the effect will be
选择框就是效果
applied to and in fact will apply some
应用于并且实际上将应用一些
effect to this audio here too and so
对这段音频的影响也在这里等等
it'll apply to the entire audio unless
它将应用于整个音频 除非
we were to cut it if we want it to only
如果我们只想剪掉它 我们就剪掉它
apply to the first half we just go to
适用于我们刚刚进入的前半部分
the razor tool and then cut and now we
剃须刀 然后剪 现在我们
have two separate we have a beginning
有两个不同的人 我们有一个开始
audio and then a later audio I'm gonna
音频 然后是稍后的音频
hit ctrl Z to undo that cut let's add
按下Ctrl Z键以撤消该剪切
one more video effect to our final last
最后的最后一个视频效果
video and let's do something really good
视频 让我们做一些真正好的事情
for this distort okay mm-hmm what's wave
对于这个扭曲好的 嗯-嗯 什么是波
a hover over it to read first wave make
将鼠标悬停在它上面 阅读第一波制作
waves on your clip with keyframes we
在您的剪辑上使用关键帧Waves
okay we don't wanna do anything with
好的 我们不想做任何事情
keyframes right now so
现在是关键帧 所以
let's do this distort plasma wheel this
让我们这样做 扭曲等离子轮子这个
hover will drag it in distort move I
悬停会将其拖入扭曲移动I
don't want to do anything too taxing
我不想做任何太累人的事
because I don't want to crash kdenlive
因为我不想撞上kdenlive
oh cool oh man so this is gonna this one
哦 酷 哦 伙计 所以这就是这一次
is gonna actually distort as it's going
实际上会随着它的发展而扭曲
it's sort of like changing the trees you
这有点像改变了你的树木
see the whole picture
看到全景
is being distorted so let's not look
被扭曲了 所以我们不要看
kind of interesting all right that's
挺有意思的 好吧 这是
kind of cool this whole thing what we
这整件事都很酷 我们
really should do is apply a a speed this
真的应该做的就是应用一个速度这个
is actually a little bit too fast but I
实际上有点太快了 但我
can just hover over and scrub through
只需在上方悬停并擦过
and we kind of see what these effects
我们可以看到这些影响
would look like in slow motion so we've
看起来像是慢动作 所以我们
got these different effects that we've
有这些不同的效果 我们有
applied to the video and that's a cool
应用到视频上 这很酷
one see that one's changing the whole
一个人看到自己正在改变整个世界
kind of video distorting and then it
一种视频失真 然后
goes back to our last one alright this
回到我们的最后一个 好的 这个
video is getting long let's apply one
视频越来越长了 让我们来应用一个
more final effect to our audio down here
更多关于我们音频的最终效果请点击此处
so under audio you noticed like if we go
所以在音频下你注意到如果我们去
to color and we try to apply a colorize
到上色 我们尝试应用上色
to our audio I don't know what it'll do
对于我们的音频 我不知道它会做什么
but I want to try it right now but what
但是我现在就想试一试 但是
we want to do there's certain effects
我们要做的是有一定的效果
that are for audio some of the effects I
这是音频的一些效果 我
will say like fade work on video and
会说像视频中的褪色作品和
audio if you want to fade in our video
如果您想在我们的视频中淡入音频
we can left-click and go to the start of
我们可以左键单击并转到
this video and it will fade in now oh
这个视频 它现在就会淡出哦
that that's not the fading in it it did
那不是它的褪色 而是它
let's see what did it do oh just kidding
让我们看看它做了什么 哦 只是开玩笑
maybe this fade in is only from audio oh
也许这淡入只是来自音频哦
we have to go fade from black that's
我们必须从黑色淡出 这是
what we do so fade from black then it'll
我们所做的一切从黑暗中褪色 然后它会
be this video clip will start a black
因为这个视频剪辑将开始一个黑色的开始
and it will fade in
它会逐渐淡出
but the fade in here is actually an
但这里的淡入实际上是一种
audio so it says fade in audio track and
音频 所以它说淡入音频轨道和
if we hover over this it says fade video
如果我们将鼠标悬停在上面 它会显示淡出视频
so some of them even though this is
所以他们中的一些人即使这是
under fade I guess what I want to say is
在褪色之下 我想我想说的是
there's audio and video effects within
里面有音频和视频效果
the same thing so you want to always
同样的事情 所以你总是想要
hover over and see if what you're doing
将鼠标悬停在上方 看看你正在做的事情
is for video or audio and if you don't
是用于视频或音频的 如果您没有
know just try and see what happens but
我知道 试着看看会发生什么
we're going to fade in the audio right
我们将淡入音频 对吧
here and then we're going to fade out
我们会时不时地淡出
the audio right here and what that does
这里的音频和它的作用
it gives us a nice so under under this
它给了我们一个很好的 所以在下面
first one we have - we have a fade in
我们的第一个-我们有一个淡入
and fade out and we can change the
淡出 我们就可以改变
duration
持续时间
let me delete the second one first so
让我先删除第二个 这样
under our fade in we see it starts with
在我们淡入的下面 我们看到它是从
this red and then it goes here so by the
这个红色 然后它放在这里 所以
end it's up to full volume and at the
最终达到最大音量 并在
start it's almost silent if we play
如果我们开始演奏 它几乎是寂静的
right now we'll see it's just gonna be
现在我们会看到这只是一场
kind of like silent then it gets louder
有点像寂静 然后变得更响亮
and louder I guess it's not that
大声点 我想不是那样的
dramatic cuz it's a short clip but we
戏剧性的因为这是一个很短的片段但是我们
can change the duration by doing this
可以通过执行此操作来更改持续时间
and it changes that triangle a little
它稍微改变了这个三角形
bit so we can see you know how quickly
这样我们就能知道你有多快
it fades in so maybe I'll do mine to
它淡出了 所以也许我会尽我所能
about there so within the first little
大约在那里 所以在第一个小的
part of the video it's up to full volume
视频的一部分达到了最大音量
then on my fade out I'll drag it on and
然后在我淡出的时候 我会拖着它
the fade out will do the same thing
淡出效果也是如此
we'll lower it so our fade-out is
我们会调低它 这样我们的淡出就是
happening at the kind of quickly at the
发生得很快 发生在
last portion of the video look and sound
视频外观和声音的最后部分
like this okay very very quick you know
像这样 好的 非常快 你知道的
little video let's render it out and see
小视频让我们把它渲染出来 看看
what happens so if we go to render I'll
会发生什么 如果我们去渲染 我会
click mp4 I will save it to my desktop
点击MP4我会将其保存到我的桌面
like I always do we'll call this bike
就像我一直做的那样 我们给这辆自行车取名为
and hit save then we can render to file
然后点击保存 我们就可以渲染到文件了
so so render out it's not taking too
所以把它渲染出来 不用花太多时间
long depending on what effects you use
很长 取决于你使用的效果
the rendering time can be very very long
渲染时间可能会非常非常长
but now will minimize we'll watch this
但现在将最小化 我们将观看这个
and see the house
然后去看看房子
[Music]
[音乐]
okay so again super short super super
好的 再来一次超短型超级型
short but at least it rendered quick and
很短 但至少它渲染得很快
I think you're getting the idea of how
我想你已经明白了
these effects work so we just drag and
这些效果起作用了 所以我们只需拖动和
drop them in and then once there's an
把它们放进去 然后一旦有一个
effect on sometimes it'll show like the
对它的影响有时会表现为
fades you can see with a little overlay
用一点叠加就能看到的渐变
and if you click on it it'll show what
如果你点击它 它会显示什么
effect it has and just like we did with
它产生了效果 就像我们在
the audio we have multiple effects you
音频我们有多重效果
can apply different effects so we can
可以应用不同的效果 因此我们可以
have two different color Corrections on
启用两种不同的颜色校正
top of the same one we have a blur and
在同一个上面 我们有一个模糊的
the color rise and then if we want to
颜色会上升 然后如果我们想
disable that effect you can actually
禁用该效果 您实际上可以
disable the blur so if you want to do a
禁用模糊 这样如果您想要执行
colorize which ones I apply that to yeah
涂上颜色 我把它应用到哪一个上
this one so if we wanted to apply this
这个 所以如果我们想要应用这个
blur this colorize we want to look at it
模糊这个颜色 我们想看看它
without the blur we can just click into
没有模糊 我们只需点击进入
hurry and quickly disable that effect
快点 快点停用那个效果
while we're changing it and then we can
当我们改变它的时候 然后我们就可以
re-enable it so that's using effects in
重新启用 以便在中使用效果
kdenlive hope you've enjoyed this video
Kdenlive希望你喜欢这段视频
go ahead and like the subscribe comment
继续并为订阅评论点赞
below and I'll catch you in the next
在下面 我会在下一个接下来的
video
视频